pinterest.com 2012-12-31

# Pinterest / Privacy Policy

**Note:** This Privacy Policy is effective as of November 8, 2012 

Thank you for using Pinterest! We wrote this policy to help you understand what information we collect, how we use it, and what choices you have regarding your information. Because we’re an Internet company, some of the concepts below are a little technical, but we’ve tried our best to explain things in a simple and clear way. We welcome your [questions and comments](https://support.pinterest.com/anonymous_requests/new) on this policy. 

## What information do we collect?

We collect information in two ways: 

### 1) When you give it to us or give us permission to obtain it.

When you sign up for or use our products, you voluntarily give us certain information. This can include your name, profile photo, pins, comments, likes, email address you used to sign up, and any other information you provide us. If you’re using Pinterest on your mobile device, you can also choose to provide us with location data. 

You also may give us permission to access your information in other services – for example, you may link your Facebook or Twitter account to Pinterest, which allows us to obtain information from those accounts (e.g., your friends or contacts). The information we obtain from those services often depends on your settings or their privacy policies, so be sure to check what those are. 

### 2) We get technical information when you use our products.

These days, whenever you use a website, mobile application, or other Internet service, there’s certain information that almost always gets created and recorded in an automated way. The same is true when you use our products, and here are some of the types of information we collect in this way: 

Log Data. When you use Pinterest, our servers automatically record information about your interaction with our products (“log data”), including information that your browser sends whenever you visit a website or your mobile app sends when you use it to access Pinterest. This log data may include your Internet Protocol address, the address of the web page you were visiting before you came to Pinterest, browser type and settings, the date and time of your request, and how you used Pinterest. 

Depending on how you’re accessing our products, we may use “cookies” (a small text file sent by your computer each time you visit our website, unique to your Pinterest account or your browser), or similar technologies to record log data. When we use cookies, we may use “session” cookies (that last until you close your browser) or “persistent” cookies (that last until you or your browser delete them). For example, we may use cookies to store your language preferences or other Pinterest settings so you don’t have to set them up every time you visit Pinterest. 

Device Information. In addition to log data, we may also collect information about the device you’re using Pinterest on, including what type of device it is, what operating system you’re using, device settings, unique device identifiers, and crash data. Whether we collect some or all of this information often depends on what type of device you’re using and its settings. For example, different types of information are available depending on whether you’re using a Mac or a PC, or an iPhone or an Android phone. To learn more about what information your device makes available to us, please also check the policies of your device manufacturer or software provider. 

## How do we use the information we collect?

We use the information we collect to provide our products to you and make them better, develop new products, and protect Pinterest and our users. For example, we may log how often people use two different versions of a product, which can help us understand which version is better. 

We also use the information we collect to offer you customized content – including helping you discover pins or boards you might like or provide you with tailored advertising. For example, if you’ve indicated that you’re interested in cooking, we may suggest food-related pins, boards, or people. 

We also use the information we collect to: 

  * send you updates (such as when certain activity, like repins or comments, happens on Pinterest), newsletters, marketing materials and other information that may be of interest to you. For example, depending on your email notification settings, we may send you weekly updates that include pins you may like. You can decide to stop getting these updates by updating your account settings (or through other settings we may provide). 
  * respond to your questions or comments. 

The information we collect may be “personally identifiable” (meaning it can be used to specifically identify you as a unique person) or “non-personally identifiable” (meaning it can’t be used to specifically identify you). We use both types of information, and combinations of both types, as described above. We may use or store information wherever Pinterest does business, including countries outside your own. 

## What choices do you have about your information?

Our goal is to give you simple and meaningful choices over your information. If you have a Pinterest account, many of the choices you have on Pinterest are built directly in to the product or your account settings. For example, you can: 

  * Access and change information in your profile page at any time, and choose whether your profile page is available to search engines;
  * Link or unlink your Pinterest account from an account on another service (e.g., Facebook or Twitter). For some services (like Facebook), you can also choose whether or not to publish your activity on Pinterest to that service.
  * Create or be added to a secret board. Secret boards are visible to you and other participants in the board, and any participant may choose to make the contents of the board available to anyone else. For example, another participant may invite someone else to the board, make the board available to an app they use to view Pinterest, or even just take an image from the board and email it to their friends. For more information about secret boards, please visit our [Help Center](http://support.pinterest.com/).
  * Close your account at any time. When you close your account, we’ll deactivate it and remove your pins and boards from Pinterest. We may retain archived copies of your information as required by law or for legitimate business purposes (including to help address fraud and spam).

In addition to the examples above, we offer other choices that you can learn more about in our [Help Center](http://support.pinterest.com/). 

In addition, you may have choices available to you through the device or software you use to access Pinterest. For example: 

  * The browser you use may provide you with the ability to control cookies or other types of local data storage;
  * Your mobile device may provide you with choices around how and whether location or other data is shared with us.

To learn more about these choices, please see the information provided by the device or software provider. 

## How is your information shared?

Pinterest is a tool people use to find their inspirations, make them a reality, and inspire others in the process. When you create public boards and pins, anyone can view them. You may also provide us with profile page information that that anyone can view. The other limited instances where we may share your personal information include: 

  * When we have your consent. This includes sharing information with other services (like Facebook or Twitter) when you’ve chosen to link to your Pinterest account to those services or publish your activity on Pinterest to them. For example, you can choose to publish your pins to Facebook or Twitter.
  * We may employ third party companies or individuals to process personal information on our behalf based on our instructions and in compliance with this Privacy Policy. For example, we may share data with a security consultant to help us get better at identifying spam or with our accountants to make sure we’re keeping the books right. In addition, some of the information we request may be collected by third party providers on our behalf. For more information about the providers we use, please see our [Help Center](https://support.pinterest.com/entries/22205721).
  * If we believe that disclosure is reasonably necessary to comply with a law, regulation or legal request; to protect the safety, rights, or property of the public, any person, or Pinterest; or to detect, prevent, or otherwise address fraud, security or technical issues.
  * We may engage in a merger, acquisition, bankruptcy, dissolution, reorganization, or similar transaction or proceeding that involves the transfer of the information described in this Policy.

We may also share aggregated or non-personally identifiable information with our partners or others. For example, we may tell a business using Pinterest how many people repinned something they shared, or the percentage of people who click a on pin after viewing it. 

##  Our Policy on Children’s Information 

Pinterest is not directed to children under 13. If you learn that your minor child has provided us with personal information without your consent, please [contact us](https://support.pinterest.com/anonymous_requests/new). 

##  How do we make changes to this policy? 

We may change this policy from time to time, and if we do we’ll post any changes on this page. If you continue to use Pinterest after those changes are in effect, you agree to the revised policy. If the changes are significant, we may provide more prominent notice or obtain your consent as required by law.

* * *

View previous Privacy Policy →

## Previous Privacy Policy

**Note:** This Privacy Policy was effective until November 8, 2012.

Unless otherwise defined in this Policy, terms used in this Policy have the same meanings as in our Pinterest Terms of Service, accessible at http://pinterest.com/about/terms/. As used in this Policy, the terms “using” and “processing” information include using cookies on a computer, subjecting the information to statistical or other analysis and using or handling information in any way, including, but not limited to collecting, storing, evaluating, modifying, deleting, using, combining, disclosing and transferring information within our organization or among our affiliates within the United States or internationally.

* * *

Pinterest, Inc. is the corporate name for Pinterest. In this Policy, we will refer to Pinterest, Inc. as “Pinterest”, “our”, “us” or “we.” 

We take your privacy seriously. We are providing this Policy to inform you of our policies and procedures regarding the collection, use and disclosure of information on our Service. We also want to inform you about your choices regarding information. If you have any questions or concerns, please let us know (see “How to contact us” section below).

Note that this Policy may be modified from time to time in our sole discretion, so check back frequently. We will notify you of any changes to the Policy by posting a new Policy and updating the “last modified” date at the top of this page.

### 1\. How we collect information

We collect information in three basic ways:

  1. We collect information that you voluntarily provide to become a registered User of our Service, and when you use certain aspects of our Service (e.g., entering an email address on a form to send an email from your Pinterest account).
  2. We collect information when you register to join Pinterest by logging into an account that you already have with certain third-party social networking sites (“SNS”) (including, but not limited to, Facebook and Twitter) via our Service. For example, our Service allows you to create an account and login to the Service using your Facebook account credentials through Facebook Connect. If you are not currently registered as a User on the Service and you click on “Sign in Using Facebook,” you will first be asked to enter your Facebook credentials and then be given the option to register and join Pinterest.
  3. When you browse or use our Service, technological tools including “Log Data” and “Cookies” collect certain information, as explained in the following section.

### 2\. What information we collect and how we use it

  1. **Personal Information.** When you register with us through the Service to become a registered User of Pinterest, we will ask you for certain information about you that can be used to contact or identify you (“Personal Information”). Personal Information may include, but is not limited to, your name, gender, profile photo, free-form biography, location/hometown, website and email address. If you decide to create your User account by logging into a SNS via the Service, you are using the Personal Information you have already provided to the SNS (such as your “real” name, email address and other information you make publicly available via the SNS) to create your User account on our Service; the information we collect may depend on the privacy settings you have with the SNS, so please consult the SNS’s privacy and data practices. For example, by using Facebook Connect, you are allowing Pinterest to access the Personal Information in your Facebook account pursuant to the Facebook Terms of Use regarding your use of the Service via Facebook.   
We use your Personal Information (in some cases, in conjunction with your “Non-Identifying Information,” see below) to provide the Service to you. For example: 
    1. **Account registration.** We create your User account for your use of the Service based upon the Personal Information you provide.
    2. **Communications.** We use your Personal Information to contact you with Pinterest newsletters, marketing or promotional materials and other information that may be of interest to you. If you decide at any time that you no longer wish to receive such communications from us, please follow the unsubscribe instructions provided in any of the communications or update your “preferences” information in your account settings. (See “Your choices regarding information,” below.)
    3. **Customer service.** We use your Personal Information to respond to your questions and/or inquiries.
    4. **Finding friends.** You also have the option to import your personal contacts (including email addresses of friend lists via SNS) to the Service so that you can find your friends on the Service, and your friends can find you on the Service.
    5. **Emailing via a Pinterest Account.** As part of the Service, Pinterest Users may communicate with other registered and non-registered Users through use of their Pinterest accounts. Where Users have selected the option of adding one or more email addresses to an online form, the message they create in the corresponding template will be sent from Pinterest to those email addresses on their behalf.
  2. **Non-Identifying Information.** We also collect other information that you provide as part of registration, the operation, and personalization of your boards on Pinterest that cannot reasonably be used to identify or contact you (e.g., without limitation, age and individual preferences) (“Non-Identifying Information”). Certain Non-Identifying Information would be considered a part of your Personal Information if it were combined with other identifiers (for example, combining your zip code with your street address) in a way that enables you to be personally identified or contacted. But the same pieces of information are considered Non-Identifying Information when they are taken alone or combined only with other Non-Identifying Information (for example, your viewing preferences) We may combine your Personal Information with Non-Identifying Information and aggregate it with information collected from other Pinterest Users to attempt to provide you with a better experience, to improve the quality and value of the Service and to analyze and understand how our Service is used. We may also use the combined information without aggregating it to serve you specifically, for instance to deliver a product to you according to your preferences or restrictions. 
  3. **Mobile Software.** Our Mobile Software allows Users to access and use the Service from their mobile devices. From the Mobile Software, you also have the option to identify the location of User Content that you wish to upload to our Service. In addition, in the event that our Mobile Software crashes on your mobile device, we will receive information about your mobile device model, software version and device carrier, which allows us to identify and fix bugs and otherwise improve the performance of our Mobile Software. 
  4. **Log Data.** When you visit the Service, whether as a registered User or a non-registered User just browsing, our servers automatically record information that your browser sends whenever you visit a website (“Log Data”). This Log Data may include information such as the browser type or the webpage you were visiting before you came to our Service, pages of our Service that you visit, the time spent on those pages, information you search for on our Service, access times and dates, and other statistics. We use this information to monitor and analyze use of the Service and the Service’s technical administration, to increase our Service’s functionality and user-friendliness, and to better tailor our Service to our visitors’ needs. For example, some of this information is collected so that when you visit the Service again, it will recognize you and the information could then be used to serve advertisements and other information appropriate to your interests. We also use this information to verify that visitors to the Service meet the criteria required to process their requests. 
  5. **Cookies.** Like many online services, Pinterest uses “cookies” on our Service to collect information. A cookie is a small data file that we transfer to your computer or mobile device’s hard disk. We use cookies for two purposes. First, we utilize “persistent” cookies to save your login information for future logins to the Service. Second, we utilize “session ID” cookies to enable certain features of the Service, to better understand how you interact with the Service and to monitor aggregate usage by Pinterest Users and web traffic routing on the Service. Unlike persistent cookies, session cookies are deleted from your computer when you log off from the Service and then close your browser. You can instruct your browser, by changing its settings, to stop accepting cookies or to prompt you before accepting a cookie from the websites you visit. If you do not accept cookies, however, you may not be able to use all portions of the Service or all functionality of the Service. (See “Your choices regarding information,” below.) 

### 3\. Sharing of your information

  1. **Pinterest Users.** When you register through the Service and submit Personal Information to create a profile or visual collection, other Pinterest Users will see your name. If you choose to provide additional Personal Information in your profile, Pinterest Users will see such additional Personal Information, including, but not limited to, your photo, location, website and biography. Providing additional Personal Information is voluntary and should correlate with the degree of interaction you want to have with Pinterest Users. We recommend that you guard and refrain from disclosing any information you consider sensitive and confidential.
  2. **Aggregate Information and Non-Identifying Information.** We may share aggregated information that does not include Personal Information and we may otherwise disclose Non-Identifying Information and Log Data with third parties for industry analysis, demographic profiling and other purposes. Any aggregated information shared in these contexts will not contain your Personal Information.
  3. **Service Providers.** We may employ third party companies and individuals to facilitate our Service, to provide the Service on our behalf, to perform Service-related services (e.g., maintenance services, database management, web analytics and improvement of the Service’s features) or to assist us in analyzing how our Service are used. These third parties have access to your Personal Information only to perform these tasks on our behalf and are obligated not to disclose or use it for any other purpose.
  4. **Social Networking Sites.** We may share the information in your Pinterest account (including your Personal Information) with the SNSs that you have linked to your Pinterest account. These third parties have access to your Personal Information only for this purpose (unless the SNS has received your Personal Information independently of the Service) and not for other purposes. 
    * **Facebook Connect and Twitter.** We allow Users to link their Facebook and Twitter accounts to our Service. Users can then post recent activity on our Service back to their Facebook and Twitter accounts. You will be prompted to decide whether or not your activity on the Service will be shared and disclosed on your Facebook/Twitter service. You can disable the foregoing feature at any time by logging into your profile and selecting the option to disable Facebook Connect and/or Twitter. Further, you may be able to edit your privacy settings for the content that you post which appears on Facebook/Twitter by making selections in your “Edit Profile” settings via the Service.
  5. **Compliance with Laws and Law Enforcement.** Pinterest cooperates with government and law enforcement officials and private parties to enforce and comply with the law. We can disclose any information about you to government or law enforcement officials or private parties as we, in our sole discretion, believe necessary or appropriate to respond to claims and legal process including, but not limited to, subpoenas, to protect the property and rights of Pinterest or a third party, to protect the safety of the public or any person, or to prevent or stop activity we may consider to be, or to pose a risk of being, illegal, unethical or legally actionable activity.
  6. **Business Transfers.** Pinterest may sell, divest, transfer, assign, share or otherwise engage in a transaction that involves, some or all of our assets, including any or all of the information described in this Policy, in the course of a corporate divestiture, merger, acquisition, joint venture, bankruptcy, dissolution, reorganization, or any other similar transaction or proceeding.

### 4\. Your choices regarding information

You have several choices regarding the use of information on our Service:

  1. **Email Communications.** If you decide at any time that you no longer wish to receive email communications from us, please follow the unsubscribe instructions provided in any of the communications or update your “preferences” information in your account settings
  2. **Cookies.** If you decide at any time that you no longer wish to accept cookies from our Service for any of the purposes described above, then you can instruct your browser, by changing its settings, to stop accepting cookies or to prompt you before accepting a cookie from the websites you visit. Consult your browser’s technical information. If you do not accept cookies, however, you may not be able to use all portions of the Service or all functionality of the Service. If you have any questions about how to disable or modify cookies, please let us know at the contact information provided below.
  3. **De-Linking SNS.** If you decide at any time that you no longer wish to have your SNS account (e.g., Facebook or Twitter) linked to your Pinterest account, then you may de-link the SNS account in the “preferences” section in your account settings.
  4. **Changing or Deleting Your Information.** All Users may review, update, correct or delete the Personal Information in their User account (including any imported contacts) by contacting us or by editing their profile via the Service. If you completely delete all of your Personal Information, then your User account may become deactivated. We will use commercially reasonable efforts to honor your request. We may retain an archived copy of your records as required by law or for legitimate business purposes. (For more information on how to control your User Content on the Pinterest Service, including information regarding the use and storage of your User Content, please see the “Sharing Your Content” section in our Terms of Service.)

### 5\. Links to other sites and services

Our Service contains links to other third-party websites and online services. If you choose to visit another website or online service by clicking on a link, you will be directed to that third party’s website or online service. The fact that we may link to a website or online service is not an endorsement, authorization or representation of our affiliation with that third party, nor is it an endorsement of their privacy or information security policies or practices. We do not exercise control over third party websites and online services, and these third parties may place their own cookies or other files on your computer and collect data or solicit Personal Information and Non-Identifying Information from you. Other sites and online services follow different rules regarding the collection, use and/or disclosure of Personal Information and Non-Identifying Information. We encourage you to read the privacy policies or statements of the other websites or online services you visit before providing any information or using such websites or services.

### 6\. How we store and protect information

  1. **Information Security.** We care about the security of your information. We use commercially reasonable safeguards to preserve the integrity and security of information collected and maintained through the Service. However, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you provide to us or guarantee that information on the Service may not be accessed, disclosed, altered, or destroyed by unauthorized persons.
  2. **Phishing.** Identity theft and the practice currently known as “phishing” are of great concern to Pinterest. Safeguarding information to help protect you from identity theft is a top priority. We do not request your credit card information, login information, or national identification numbers in a non-secure or unsolicited e-mail or telephone communication. For more information about phishing, visit the Federal Trade Commission’s [website](http://www.ftc.gov/).
  3. **Breach Notification.** We will make any legally required disclosures of any breach of the security, confidentiality, or integrity of stored “personal data” (as defined in applicable state statutes on security breach notification) to you via email or conspicuous posting on this Service in the most expedient time possible and without unreasonable delay, insofar as consistent with (i) the legitimate needs of law enforcement or (ii) any measures necessary to determine the scope of the breach and restore the reasonable integrity of the data system.
  4. **International Transfer .** Your information may be transferred to — and maintained on — computers located outside of your state, province, country or other governmental jurisdiction where the privacy laws may not be as protective as those in your jurisdiction. If you are located outside the United States and choose to provide information to us, Pinterest transfers Personal Information to the United States and processes it there. Your consent to this Privacy Policy followed by your submission of such information represents your agreement to that transfer.

### 7\. Our policy towards children’s information

This Service is not directed to children under 13. We do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under 13. If a parent or guardian becomes aware that his or her child has provided us with Personal Information without their consent, he or she should [contact us](https://support.pinterest.com/anonymous_requests/new). If we become aware that a child under 13 has provided us with Personal Information, we will delete such information from our files.

### 8\. How to contact us

If you have any questions about this Policy or any of the practices described herein, please contact us at 572 7th Street, San Francisco, CA, 94107, call us at 650-561-5407, or use our [contact form](https://support.pinterest.com/anonymous_requests/new).
